today I'll show you how to implement
chat with your document system in just
four lines of code I recently started
exploring llama index which is an
alternative to link chain just like link
chain Lama index gives us the ability to
build powerful applications based on
large language models these applications
include document q a
data augmented chat box knowledge agents
the great part is you can connect
different types of data sources
including structured and structured and
semi-structured data sources so using
lamb index you can quickly build llm
based applications just like Lang chain
the main reason for me of exploring Lama
index was the ability to fine-tune
embedding models to improve the
performance of document Q and A systems
using large language models so basically
that means you can not only find during
the large language model on your data
set but you can also fine tune their
betting model and that will improve the
performance of your recruited system
I'll cover this topic in a future video
in this first video I'll show you how to
build a chat with your document system
using Lama index you probably have seen
this diagram before so there are
different components the first component
is basically loading your documents then
you want to divide your documents into
smaller chunks with a predefined chunk
size so each of the chunks you compute
different embeddings these embeddings
are numerical representations of the
text contained in a chunk then you
create a semantic index so basically
this is your vector strap after that you
can actually use the swipe to store to
chat with your documents now in order to
chat with your document
the system takes your questions compute
the same embedding as the embedding it
computed for the chunks then performed a
semantic search on your knowledge base
so
as a result of this search it will
return
a certain number of chunks that are
relevant to your question so let's say
by default number index returns only two
chunks out of all the chunks available
in the knowledge base
and these return chunks will be used as
a context to the llm of your choosing so
the llm gets the question from the user
along with the context that was written
by the embedding model during the
semantic search and the llm will
generate a response and that is going to
be shown to the user as you can see this
whole process can be divided into four
different steps and I'll show you how to
implement this whole process using just
four lines of codes within gamma index
okay so let's start looking at the code
so I'm using Google Chrome in order to
the notebook and the code so first we're
installing all the required packages so
we are installing lamba index then open
AI so for the initial example I will
show you how to implement the document q
a using open a llm and open AI
embeddings but I'll also show you how to
replace the openai llm within open
source llm from hanging face
and for that we will need Transformers
package to access the hug interface
based llms and the accelerate package in
order to accelerate the processing or
speed of running local llms
now for the initial example we will need
the open AI API key in order to access
open AIS embeddings and llm so you'll
need to provide those
okay next we need to import the required
packages so we are importing open AI
from lamba index then we are inputting
two auxiliary functions
or objects one is e Vector store index
and the other one is a simple directory
reader the use will become clearer when
we look at the code and then we are also
importing some packages just to properly
format the output from the model now in
order to chat with your documents you
will first need access to those
documents so the way I'm going to do it
is I will create a folder called Data
and within this folder I will upload
this file now this specific essay is
titled what I worked on and this is
basically an essay written by allgram
when he was working with y combinators
so we're going to be using this as an
example data set but you can upload any
type of documents for example text Word
documents or PDFs now going back to the
architecture first we will need to load
the documents now Lama index provides a
very simple functionality to do that so
there's this class called Simple
directory reader you simply need to
provide the name of the folder or path
of the folder so in this case our folder
is called data and that's why I provided
the name data then we need to call the
load data function on top of that and
that will load our documents
now the great thing about this is you
can have different type of documents
within the folder and this class will
Define which loader to use with those
documents
and we can also look at it this is
basically the text file and the whole
text file is loaded in here
now the next step in our architecture is
to create a vector store so this
involves dividing your documents into
chunks Computing their beddings and then
storing both the embeddings as well as
the chunks in a vector store
again the number index makes this very
easy we're going to use the vector store
index class then we are going to be
creating the vector store from documents
we'll pass on our documents in here and
this will create a vector store index
for us
okay so we just created our index now
next we are going to look at how to
customize different options for example
the chunk size the type of embeddings
and everything but before that we just
want to ask questions so for that we
need to create a query engine
now I find this to be very streamlined
in Nama index compared to
so here basically you can
create a query engine on the index by
using the as query engine now
if you want to chat with your documents
and want to have memory so you were
going to use a function called as
chatbot and that will basically enable
memory but as a query engine you don't
have the memory component in here now in
order to use this pretty engine to get a
response based on the user question so
it has to go through this process that
it needs to compute embeddings for the
question then do the semantic search and
use the returned chunks as context with
the lln along with the question to get
to generate an answer all of this is an
implemented using a single line of code
but basically what you do is you use the
query engine then call this function
called query and you pass on your
question to this function so for example
the question that we are asking is what
did the author do growing up and we will
get a response in here now the response
that you get has a lot of different
components in care but we're simply
interested in in the answer
I'll show you what all this text means
in a bit but first let me show you how
to get the answer from the llm for that
we will use the display function from
IPython and put the response in markdown
and also bold it so here's the answer
from the model the author worked on
writing and programming outside of the
school before College they wrote short
stories and tried writing programs on an
IBM 1401 computer using an early version
of quadrant right so this is the answer
that was generated by the llm using the
context provided by the embedding model
as you can see
apart from the Imports we were able to
build a document q a system using just
all lines of codes
and this implementation is very clean
next I want to show you how to customize
different parts of this diagram for
example how do you define the chunk size
chunk or left or how do you change the
llm and so on and so forth but before
that let's look at some very important
Concepts when it comes to the vector
stores so right now the index that we
created is just in memory but you can
persist this by calling this function
persist on the index that you created
now the way it's going to work is if we
run this so by default it's going to
create a folder called storage and
within this you will see multiple Json
files now this functionality is critical
because it enables you to create the
index one
install it on your
disk and then use it in your future runs
right now in order to load a vector
store that was stored on the disk we're
going to be using the storage context
along with the load index from Storage
class
now the way it works is that you will
use a storage context to read the
content of the index and then from the
storage context that you just created
you are going to recreate the index
right and then you can use it exactly
the way we did it before
now I hope this is clear another
question that comes in mind is what
exactly is in this Vector store
now in order to show you I'm going to
open all these four files and the two
important files that we want to look at
is the stock stored and the vector Stone
so the vector store as you can see here
is basically the embeddings that we
computed for each of the chunk and
depending on the embedding model that
you choose you are going to get
different number of embeddings per chunk
now similar to the vector store for
embeddings there is a doc store so here
you will see different chunks from the
document so basically this is text that
is to add in two different chunks and
the third most important thing is index
store basically this has the hash or
address for different chunks and using
this index tool it determines which
embeddings in here belongs to which
chunk
now when you create in a vector store so
it's going to store both the embeddics
that it computed as well as the original
chunks from the documents
now during the retrieval process the llm
is going to have access to both the
embeddings as well as the chunks that
are retrieved based on the embedding
model I hope this is clear now let's
look at some of the customizations that
you can make the first customization
that we are going to be looking at is
how to change the llm now in order to
change the default values we are going
to be using the concept of service
context so this defines all the default
values of different parameters within
lamba index
Now by default I think that llm lamb
index uses is The DaVinci zero three
model however if you want to change it
to let's say GPT 3.5 turbo so we
basically use the open AI function
within in Lamb index create an llm based
on that so you can Define the
temperature the max number of tokens
that is going to generate right and then
ask that llm
to this service context to change the
defaults so here we're changing the
default llm to GPT 3.5 and then ask that
Ellen to the vector store index that we
just created
and then you can use the vector store
index exactly the way we used above now
if you want to use another llm such as
let's say Google Palm so again you can
simply import the Palm llm from gamma
index llm class then pass that from
added in to the edit and within the
service context that will basically
change the default value and then again
you can pass it exactly like here to the
vector store index and then it will
start using the Palm llm in this case
again you will need to set the API key
for pump but the process is going to be
very similar to what we did for open AI
model now another parameter which is
very important when it comes to these
chat Bots for your documents is the
chunk size so in order to change the
channel size we can follow the same
pattern so here you can simply pass on
and Define two other parameters so the
first is the check size the second was
one is chunk overlap so here I'm using a
thousand tokens for example with an
overlap of 20 tokens
so I would recommend everybody to look
at the documentations and see what the
default values are and how you can
change them in here now another way of
doing this is you can set the global
Service context so in that case you
don't have to pass it to the vector
store index that you create you simply
set the global Service contract using
the service context that you just
created and then you can use the those
as defaults in the rest of your code now
in this last example I'll show you how
to use an open source llm from hugging
face and the way you do it is we we're
importing the hearing phase Ln class
mlama index llms then you can also
import prompt template from the prompts
class this is very similar to what you
probably have seen in that chain right
so here's basically the system prompt
because some of the open source elements
need a system prompt but this system
prompt is specifically for the stable LM
models in close the user query within
some special tokens right now in order
to use the llm
it's basically using lamba CPP in the
background so we create an llm based on
different parameters so for example the
context window you can pass this on
maximum new tokens that you want to
generate right and other parameters such
as the temperature that you want to set
you want to do sampling or not right
then you need to pass the model name as
well as the token as a name this system
prompt if the model supports one then
the prompt template with the create user
query right if you have multiple
gpus and you want to all use all of them
you can set the device map to Auto now
in some certain cases there are certain
specific tokens
that are going to be used as stopping
IDs you can pass on those depending on
the model that you're using because
different models are going to be using
different tokenizes right so these are
different parameters you can set
essentially this will create an llm
class now you can simply pass that
editing class to the service context
that we created right along with the
setup chunk size that we want to use
this will set the default element to
this hugging face llm and then you can
do query on your web restore and this
alert them is going to be used for
generating the responses now this was a
quick overview of how to build a
document q a system you using gamma
index now learner index is extremely
powerful that it has some really cool
features for example one of the
applications that I'm currently looking
at is how to fine-tune embedding models
along with fine tuning the additives uh
so this is going to be the first video
in the series on the number index I will
be creating more advanced tutorials and
on the on different topics and different
features that Rama index have if you
like what you see on the channel and
would like to support it check out my
patreon now if you want to build a q a
system and want to use LinkedIn instead
of lava index I would recommend you to
check out this video as always if you
found the content helpful consider
liking the video and subscribe to the
channel thanks for watching and see you
in the next one